# Olamide Adeniyi

# Full Stack Developer

Marie → https://www.oladev.net → https://linkedin/in/adeniyi-olamide → \_oladev

https://www.github.com/holahmide

#### **PROFILE**

I am a full stack web developer with 4 years of experience and proven knowledge of programming and perseverance, through discipline and deliberate practice of conventional and modern concepts in software engineering. I enjoy solving complex problems using web technologies and building products that make an impact.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Frontend Development**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, NextJS, VueJS, Vuex, NuxtJS, GatsbyJS, Gridsome, SCSS, Sass, TailwindCSS, Chakra UI, SEO.

#### **Backend Development**

JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Prisma, Laravel, Lumen, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, REST API, Jest, Git, CI/CD, AWS, Firebase.

#### **Soft Skils**

Agile, Curiosity, Adaptability, Problem Solving, Critical, thinking, Time Management, Communication, Leadership, Persistence.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Full Stack Developer** 03/2022 – 09/2022

Jetron Mall &

- Built an extremely scalable web application with a team of 4 developers. Enforced accessibility standards and best practices for the codebase and application development. Ensured the web application was SEO compliant allowing search engines to index it efficiently.
- Experienced the use of React, NextJS, Typescript, TDD, PDF creation kits and GraphQL.

Full Stack Developer 06/2021 – 04/2022

**Brigow Homes** 

- Using modern technologies including React and NextJS, figma designs were converted to web pages.
- Built a robust API Backend application using NodeJS with GraphQL and REST API. Enforced healthy codebases, coding styles and standard.
- Improved the deployment speed of the Frontend application.

**Full Stack Developer** 12/2020 – 05/2021

Hellio Solutions &

- Implemented complex features using PHP and Javascript such as reading an excel file with large amount of customer contacts. Crafted, audited and improved designs, accessibility and the overall experience of the product.
- Increased File loading and reading time by 80% during a test case of 600,000 contacts in an excel document uploaded on the server.

**Full Stack Developer** 07/2020 – 12/2020

Urella

- Built a church management application for a startup with a team of web developers. Implemented attendance tracking, financial record keeping, membership authentication, data presentation and visualization, COVID-19 seat tracker and crowd control.
- Development technologies include Laravel, PHP, JavaScript and VueJS.

**Full Stack Developer** 05/2019 – 09/2020

Gilgal House Media &

- Built an extremely scalable web application and obtained relevant experiences in data administration, hosting, web server management, CI/CD and Git.
- Built a CBT application for the company to access new recruits based on some preset questions and interview parameters. Enhanced HR team recruitment method accuracy by 90%. Introduced automated mailing and attendance update alert features.

**Full Stack Developer** 02/2019 – 09/2019

Freelance @

Built and maintained stunning web application for my clients.

# **EDUCATION**

# BEng. Information Engineering

07/2017

Landmark University &

Best Department Graduating Student with a CGPA of 4.86.

### **COURSES**

### React - The Complete Guide.

**Udemy** 

By Maximilian Schwarzmüller

# **Advanced CSS and Sass**

**Udemy** 

By Jonas Schmedtmann

# Javascript Essential Training

LinkedIn

By Morten Rand-Hendriksen

# **Project Management**

Landmark University